let's look at the solution to our latest
virtual to physical translation quiz
where we had the memory access times and
the hit rates for the cache and we were
assuming that the three level page table
now can be cached just like data with
the same hit rate
now we have one cycle to compute the
virtual address
followed by for each level of the page
table
three times we need to do
one cycle to access the cache
plus
10 of the time for each of those
we will have a miss and go to memory to
fetch the page table entry
and then after we do that
we can access the data
which takes one cycle plus
ten percent of the time it takes ten
more cycles to access memory
so now we have
nine cycles all together
six of which
are used
by our virtual to physical translation
and only three
for
the instruction itself and the memory
access
including the misses so we can see that
the virtual to physical translation is
expensive even if we allow page table
entries to be treated as data and cached